(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
沙花叉クロヱ 2nd Anniversary 3D LIVE
沙花叉アニソンフェス
Sakamata Chloe 2nd Anniversary 3D LIVE
Sakamata Chloe Anison Fes
SAKAMATA CHLOE 2nd ANNIVERSARY
2023.11.29
SAKAMATA CHLOE ANNIVERSARY LIVE ANIME SONG FES
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
博衣こより
Hakui Koyori
紫咲シオン
Murasaki Shion
白銀ノエル
Shirogane Noel
沙花叉クロヱ
Sakamata Chloe
宝鐘マリン
Houshou Marine
森カリオペ
Mori Calliope
星街すいせい
Hoshimachi Suisei
SPECIAL GUEST ???
沙花叉クロヱ アニソンフェス 2nd Anniv.
Sakamata Chloe Anisong Fes 2nd Anniv.
沙花叉アニソンフェス、スタート！
Sakamata Anisong Fes, start!
DANZEN! ふたりはプリキュア
Absolutely! We Are Pretty Cure
プリキュア！ プリキュア！
Pretty Cure! Pretty Cure!
プリティでキュアキュア ふたりはプリキュア！
Pretty and Cure-Cure, the two of us are Pretty Cure!
いっちょやって　まだいっちょ
Do it once, then once more
ぶっちゃけありえない
To be honest, it's impossible
制服着ててもふたりは
Even wearing uniforms, the two of us
むちゃくちゃタフだし
Are super tough
お互いピンチを乗り越えるたび
Every time we overcome a pinch together
強く　近くなるね
We get stronger and closer
Your best, my best
生きてるんだから
Because we're alive
失敗なんてメッチャない
Failure doesn't mean much at all
笑う門に福来るでしょ
Good fortune comes to those who laugh, right?
ネガティブだってブッ飛ぶ
Even negativity will fly away
命の華
The flower of life
咲かせて　思い切り
Make it bloom with all your might
もっとバリバリ
More and more vigorously
プリキュア！ プリキュア！
Pretty Cure! Pretty Cure!
プリティでキュアキュア ふたりはプリキュア！
Pretty and Cure-Cure, the two of us are Pretty Cure!
たまには放課後　ホホント
Sometimes, after school, just relaxing
おしゃべり　ベリーたい
Want to chat-chat so much
噂は恋する乙女の
Rumors are like vitamins
ビタミン剤だもん
For a girl in love
闇夜に浮かんだ虹の架け橋
A rainbow bridge floating in the dark night
ここに降りて　奇跡
Come down here, it's a miracle
Your best, my best
全力だから
Because it's full power
友情・愛情・最高！
Friendship, love, it's the best!
何よりそこの輝くエクボ
More than anything, those shining dimples
必殺技でハートキュン！
A special move to make your heart throb!
瞳に星
With stars in your eyes
映して　思い切り
Reflecting them with all your might
もっとキラキラ
More and more sparkling
プリキュア！ プリキュア！
Pretty Cure! Pretty Cure!
プリティでキュアキュア ふたりはプリキュア！
Pretty and Cure-Cure, the two of us are Pretty Cure!
プリキュア！ プリキュア！
Pretty Cure! Pretty Cure!
明日は明日の風吹く
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow
舵向きわかんない
I don't know which way the rudder points
今しかできない宿題
Homework that can only be done now
頑張らなくちゃ
We have to do our best
真逆のキャラでも　相槌ってる
Even with opposite characters, we're in sync
夢は　生きる力
Dreams are the power to live
Your best, my best
生きてるんだから
Because we're alive
失敗なんてメッチャない
Failure doesn't mean much at all
笑う門に福来るでしょ
Good fortune comes to those who laugh, right?
ネガティブだってブッ飛ぶ
Even negativity will fly away
命の華
The flower of life
咲かせて　思い切り
Make it bloom with all your might
もっとバリバリ
More and more vigorously
プリキュア！ プリキュア！
Pretty Cure! Pretty Cure!
プリティでキュアキュア ふたりはプリキュア！
Pretty and Cure-Cure, the two of us are Pretty Cure!
プリキュア！ プリキュア！
Pretty Cure! Pretty Cure!
Someone! Someone! Someone Else!
SOMEONE ELSE
誰でも好きだ
I like anyone
思われたくない
I don't want to be thought of like that
もっとギュッと距離は埋めてみようよ
Let's try to close the distance more tightly
まつられて好きだ
I like being adored
染まるのは恋だ
Being dyed is love
一歩ずつここで過ごしていたいよ
I want to spend time here, step by step
ハート遠くにユートピアが見えるよ
I can see Utopia far away in my heart
君の瞳の温泉に入りたい
I want to get into the hot spring of your eyes
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
まっしぐら　コンコン　チャイムを打たれたなら
If the chime is struck head-on, ding-dong
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
打たれちゃったら　産毛フワフワ　ドリームなでられたなら
If it's struck, and my fluffy downy hair is stroked in a dream
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
進め切なさ　ほろにの真ん中　射抜かれたなら
Advance, sorrow, if the bittersweet center is pierced
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
射抜かれちゃったら　狂おしグビリ　骨が感じてるなら
If it's pierced, and my bones feel a maddening gulp
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
汗をかきましょう
Let's work up a sweat
ワン！ワン！ワン！　ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One! One! One! One!
汗をかきましょう
Let's work up a sweat
ワン！ワン！ワン！　ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One! One! One! One!
みんな今は好きだ　あなたは明日
I love everyone right now; you'll be tomorrow
素っ頓狂　自然しないでちょうだい
Please don't act so strangely and naturally
くじけんのが好きだ　願望が開いた
I like not losing heart; my desire has opened up
グッとじっとこらえて　萌えられてみたいよ
Endure it firmly and still; I want to try being 'moe-fied'
ワン！ワン！ワン！　ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One! One! One! One!
あぁ　宇宙に薔薇の楽園が見える
Ah, I can see a rose paradise in space
の甘い隙間の　VIVID SEXY WAR
In the sweet gaps, a VIVID SEXY WAR
窓の向こうに　エデンの園　開いたなら
If the Garden of Eden opens outside the window
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
開いたちゃったら　ぼんやり壁に　気ままな模様描いたなら
If it's opened, and a carefree pattern is drawn on the dim wall
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
瞳にズンと　異次元くり抜かれたなら
If another dimension is hollowed out deep in my eyes
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
くり抜かれたら　指げそりと　本音を暴かれたなら
If it's hollowed out, and my true feelings are exposed with a thin finger
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
暴かれちゃったら　進め寂しさ　ほろにの真ん中射抜かれたなら
If it's exposed, advance, loneliness, if the bittersweet center is pierced
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
射抜かれちゃったら　困った切れ味　爽やか立ち回れたなら
If it's pierced, if I can move with a sharp and refreshing grace
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
ウィンク飛ばしましょう
Let's blow a wink
Someone else! Someone else! Someone else!
瞳にズンと　異次元くり抜かれたなら
If another dimension is hollowed out deep in my eyes
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
くり抜かれたら　指げそりと　本音を暴かれたなら
If it's hollowed out, and my true feelings are exposed with a thin finger
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
暴かれちゃったら　進め寂しさ　ほろにの真ん中射抜かれたなら
If it's exposed, advance, loneliness, if the bittersweet center is pierced
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
射抜かれちゃったら　困った切れ味　爽やか立ち回れたなら
If it's pierced, if I can move with a sharp and refreshing grace
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
ウィンク飛ばしましょう
Let's blow a wink
高鳴り　ドコドコ　ドラムを叩かれたなら
If the drum is beaten with a thumping heart
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
叩かれちゃったら　うずきがジクジク　ハート見透かされたなら
If it's beaten, and the aching heart is seen through
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
開く油断とりしろ　ベリーベリー　計られたなら
The opening of carelessness, if very very measured
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
計られちゃったら　物惜しげにじわじわ　ジク膨らんだなら
If it's measured, and it swells up bit by bit reluctantly
ワン！ワン！ワン！
One! One! One!
走り出しましょう
Let's start running
ウィンク飛ばしましょう
Let's blow a wink
Someone else! Someone else! Someone else! Someone else!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
The Everlasting Guilty Crown
あぁ... 世界は終わりを告げようとしている
Ah... the world is about to meet its end
誰にも止められはしない
No one can stop it
始まる崩壊のシンフォニーが鳴り響いて
The symphony of beginning collapse resounds
降る雨はまるで涙の音色
The falling rain is like the sound of tears
あぁ　教えて
Ah, tell me
支配し支配され人たちは
People who rule and are ruled over...
いつかその心に憎しみを
...will they one day have hatred in their hearts...
そして愛することも...
...and even loving...
自由を あらわす
Expressing freedom
その
That
この歌が聴こえてる
You can hear this song
命あるすべてのものよ
All living things
真実はあなたの胸の中にある
The truth is within your heart
嵐の海を行く時も
Even when crossing stormy seas
決して屈することのない強さを
A strength that never gives in
くれるから
Because it gives me that
けれども進むほど風は強い
But the further I go, the stronger the wind
希望の光はやがて消えていく
The light of hope will eventually fade
「よこせ」と奪い合い 果てに人は
People fight and snatch, and in the end,
殺し合う 涙さえ枯れ果てて
Kill each other, until even tears dry up
気付いて その目は互いを認めるため
Realize, those eyes are for recognizing each other
その声は想いを伝えるため
That voice is for conveying feelings
その手は大事な人とつなぐためにある
Those hands are for holding onto loved ones
この歌が聴こえてる
You can hear this song
世界中の夜標のものよ
O guides of the night across the world
希望はあなたの胸の中にある
Hope is within your heart
燃え盛る炎の中でも
Even amidst the blazing flames
決して傷つくことのない強さを
A strength that will never be hurt
くれるから
Because it gives me that
その手で守ろうとしたものは
Was what you tried to protect with those hands
愛するものだったのだろうか
Something that you loved?
赤く染まったその手を眺めて
Looking at those blood-stained hands
やっと自覚してきた重さを
The weight you finally realized
過ちと認めるその罪を
The sin of admitting it as a mistake
止めどなく溢れるその涙を知る
Knowing those tears that overflow endlessly
この歌が聴こえてる
You can hear this song
命あるすべてのものよ
All living things
真実はあなたの胸の中にある
The truth is within your heart
嵐の海は静まった
The stormy sea has calmed
失ったものは数えきれなくとも
Even if what was lost is beyond count
この歌が聴こえてる
You can hear this song
世界中の夜標のものよ
O guides of the night across the world
希望はあなたの胸の中にある
Hope is within your heart
悲しみの夜を越える時
When crossing the night of sorrow
必ずあなたが生きていく強さを
The strength to surely keep on living
持ってるから
Because you have it within you
超天変地異みたいな狂騒にも慣れて
Getting used to an uproar like a catastrophe
こんな日常を平和と見間違う
Mistaking this daily life for peace
狂っておちてコースター 揺さぶられながら
Going crazy and falling off the coaster while being shaken
見失えないものは何だ？
What is it that I cannot lose sight of?
平等性原理主義の概念に呑まれて
Swallowed by the concept of egalitarian fundamentalism
心までがまるでエトセトラ
Even my heart is just an "et cetera"
大嫌い 大好き ちゃんと喋らなきゃ
Hate it, love it, I've got to speak up properly
人形とさして変わらないし
Otherwise I'm not much different from a doll
あぁ 宵街を行く人だかりは
Ah, the crowds moving through the evening streets
嬉しそうだったり 寂しそうだったり
Look happy, look lonely
コントラストが五線を飛びまわり
The contrast flies around the staff
歌とリズムになる
Becoming song and rhythm
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & Sugar Song, Peanuts & Bitter Step
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
It's sweet and bitter, it makes my head spin
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Let's head south-southwest and keep the party going
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
It'll be a night that surprises the whole world
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクト
I feel great, becoming a chain and reflecting
蓋然性合理主義の正義に呑まれて
Swallowed by the justice of probabilistic rationalism
僕らの音楽は道具になりさがる
Our music degenerates into a tool
こっちを向いてよ 背を向けないでよ
Look this way, don't turn your back on me
それは正論にならないけど
That doesn't make it the right thing to say
祭囃子のその後で 高ぶったままの人
After the festival music, those who are still excited
泣き出し出してしまう人
Those who burst into tears
多分同じだけど 言葉にしようものなら
They're probably the same, but if I were to put it into words
稚拙なものばかり
It would be nothing but childish things
最高だってシュガーソング、幸せってビターステップ
Sugar Song is the best, Bitter Step is happiness
死ねない理由をそこに映し出せ
Reflect the reason you can't die right there
惜しがったって等速で明日は来ちゃうけど
Even if you regret it, tomorrow will come at the same speed
脳内天国お花畑のアップデートを果たしたのなら
If you've updated the flower garden in your head
someday 狂騒が息を潜めても
Someday, even if the frenzy catches its breath
someday 正論に意味がなくなっても
Someday, even if the right argument loses its meaning
feeling 探すまで 鳴らし続けることだけが
Feeling, until we find it, just continuing to ring
僕たちを僕たちたらしめる証明になる Q.E.D.
Will be the proof that makes us who we are. Q.E.D.
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & Sugar Song, Peanuts & Bitter Step
生きてく理由をそこに映し出せ
Reflect the reason you live right there
北北東は後退り その距離が誇らしい
Backing away from the north-northeast, proud of that distance
世界中を驚かせ続けよう
Let's keep surprising the whole world
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & Sugar Song, Peanuts & Bitter Step
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
It's sweet and bitter, it makes my head spin
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Let's head south-southwest and keep the party going
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
It'll be a night that surprises the whole world
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクト
I feel great, becoming a chain and reflecting
Goes on 一回だって、いつだって、また一興
Goes on, even once, anytime, it's a blast again
一回だって、いつだって、また一興
Even once, anytime, it's a blast again
nananana... you got the heart base in the melody
この瞳は 鮮やかに 今 君しか映さない
These eyes clearly reflect only you now
踏み込んで目覚める 世界へ
Stepping into the awakening world
Chase the world
俯きすぎて 小さい地平
Looking down too much, a small horizon
僕だけの景色が
The scenery only for me
組み立てたジオラマの 嘘だと
As a lie of the assembled diorama
合わせづらい視点に 気づいている
I'm aware of the point of view that's hard to align
描き出して行く未来を 美しさを
The future that I'm drawing out, the beauty
手に
In my hands
それぞれが飛べる場所を 追いかけていく
Chasing the places where each can fly
この瞳は 鮮やかに 今 君しか映さない
These eyes clearly reflect only you now
加速して初めて
Only after accelerating
…行ける僕は　僕の叫べ
...I can go, my cry
もっと高く　もっと強く
Higher, stronger
君に届けたい
I want to reach you
踏み込んで目覚める
Step in and wake up
Chase the world!
万言も混ざり続けて
Countless words keep mixing together
擦り切れてしまった
They've worn out
諦めてしまえという
A voice telling me to give up
もしや
Perhaps...
屈服させた壁を壊したがってる
...it wants to break the walls that made me yield
ひたむきに祈る声も
Even the voice praying earnestly
闇に笑われる夜に
In the night laughed at by darkness
叶わない戯言さと
Calling it impossible nonsense
潜ませても
Even if I hide it
この翼で　誰よりも
With these wings, more than anyone
はるか羽ばたく
I'll fly far away
抑えない鼓動が
If this uncontrollable heartbeat
運命を急がせるのなら
Makes destiny rush forward
願う前に　戻る前に
Before wishing, before returning
君を抱きしめて
I'll hold you close
彼方へと飛び立つ
And take flight to the other side
Changing your world!
この瞳は　鮮やかに舞う
These eyes vividly witness
君しか知らない
Only you, who dances through them
加速して初めて
Only by accelerating
行ける僕は　僕の叫べ
Can I go, hear my cry
この翼で　誰よりも
With these wings, more than anyone
はるか羽ばたく
I'll fly far away
抑えない鼓動が
If this uncontrollable heartbeat
運命を急がせるのなら
Makes destiny rush forward
もっと高く　もっと強く
Higher, stronger
君に届けたい
I want to reach you
踏み込んで目覚める
Step in and wake up
世界へ！
To the world!
May'nさん、来てください本当にありがとうございます！
May'n-san, thank you so much for coming!
ありがとうございます。2周年おめでとうございます！
Thank you. Congratulations on your 2nd anniversary!
ありがとうございます。もう、嬉しすぎて、ちょっと、歌が、本当に上手すぎて。
Thank you. I'm just so happy... and your singing was just too good.
めちゃめちゃびっくりしまして、本当に。みんなびっくりしてます、今。
I was so surprised, really. Everyone is surprised right now.
嬉しいです。でもこうやってご一緒させてもらえて。
I'm glad. To be able to perform together like this...
いやもう緊張しました。
I was so nervous.
だって、色んな、例えば「ライオン」とか「射手座」とかも歌っていただいてましたもんね、以前。
Because you've covered various songs like "Lion" and "Iteza" before, right?
あ、そんな、バレてるんですね！
Oh, you noticed that!
なんか「ライオン」はもともと私お二人で歌わせてもらってる楽曲なので。
Since "Lion" is originally a song I sing as a duo...
お一人で、あんなにまた違う風に歌えるなんてと思って、すごい嬉しく思ってます。
I was really happy to see you sing it alone in such a different way.
嬉しい！こちらこそ、本当にありがとうございます。
I'm so happy! Thank you so much as well.
え、VTuberコラボが初めてってお伺いしたんですけど。
I heard this is your first VTuber collaboration?
あ、そうなんです。なので、こうやって、あと自分の楽曲を他の方がカバーしてくださって、
Yes, it is. So, having someone else cover my song...
で、一緒に歌うっていう経験も、実はアーティスト同士のコラボも少なくて、自分の曲だと。
and then singing it together... actually, even with other artists, I don't do that often with my own songs.
あ、そうなんですか。
Oh, really?
なので、今回かなり、VTuberの方とのコラボっていう意味でも、めちゃめちゃ特別ですし。
So this time, in terms of collaborating with a VTuber, it's very special.
本当に「初めて」がたくさん詰まったコラボでした。
It was a collaboration filled with many "firsts."
やったー！嬉しいです、ありがとうございます。
Yay! I'm so happy, thank you.
なんかめちゃめちゃ本当に緊張してて。
I was really, really nervous.
なんか、ご挨拶に行く時とかも、「どうしよう、どうしよう」と思ってて。
When I went to greet you, I was thinking "What should I do, what should I do?"
ちょっと失礼がないように行かなきゃと思って。
I thought I had to go without being rude.
で、ちょっとメイク中ってお伺いしたんで、ガチャって開けたら、May'nさんがメイクまだされてる最中で。
And I heard you were in the middle of makeup, so when I opened the door, May'n-san was still being made up.
で、その時に「May'nがメインじゃない時なんですけど」って言ってて。
And then you said, "It's a time when May'n isn't 'main' (complete) yet."
めっちゃ… まだなんか化粧水のあとの乳液の段階だったんで、ベトベトの、ベトベトのメインになる前みたいな状態で。
I was... just at the stage of moisturizer after toner, so it was like sticky, sticky pre-main state.
いや、もうそんなの、気にならないぐらい本当に…
Oh, it didn't bother me at all, really...
いや本当に、で、めっちゃそれで気さくな方で、マジで安心しました。
No really, you were so friendly, I was truly relieved.
嬉しいです。ありがとうございます。
I'm glad. Thank you.
本当にありがとうございます。今日は楽しんでいただけましたでしょうか。
Thank you so much. Did you enjoy yourself today?
あ、すごい楽しかったです。ぜひまた今度コラボさせてください。
Oh, it was a lot of fun. Please let me collaborate with you again sometime.
ぜひともよろしくお願いします！ありがとうございます。
By all means, please! Thank you.
ではまだまだライブは続きますので、皆さんよろしくお願いします。
Well, the live show continues, so everyone, please enjoy.
ありがとうございます。皆さん、まだまだ楽しんでいってください。
Thank you. Everyone, please keep having fun.
2周年本当におめでとうございました。
Congratulations again on your 2nd anniversary.
本当にありがとうございましたー！バイバーイ！
Thank you so much! Bye-bye!
only my railgun
放て 心に刻んだ夢を
Release the dream etched in your heart,
未来さえも置き去りにして
leaving even the future behind.
限界など知らない 意味ない
I know no limits, they're meaningless.
この力が光散らす
This power scatters light.
その先に遥かな想いを
Beyond that, far-reaching thoughts.
歩いてきたこの道を振り返ることしかできないなら
If I can only look back at this path I've walked,
今ここで全てを壊せる
I can destroy everything right here, right now.
暗闇に落ちる街並み
The streets falling into darkness,
人はどこまで立ち向かえるの
how far can people stand up to it?
加速するその痛みから
From that accelerating pain,
誰かをきっと守れるよ
I'm sure I can protect someone.
Looking the blitz loop this planet to search a way
Only my railgun can shoot it 今すぐ
Only my railgun can shoot it, right now.
身体中を光の速さで
At the speed of light through my whole body,
駆け巡った 確かな予感
a certain premonition coursed through.
掴め！ 望むものなら残さず
Seize it! If it's what you desire, leave nothing behind,
輝ける自分らしさで
shining with your own identity.
信じてるよ あの日の誓いを
I believe in the oath of that day.
この瞳に光る涙
Even the tears shining in these eyes,
それさえも強さになるから
even they will become strength.
立ち止まると少しだけ
When I stop, I feel a little bit
感じる切なさに
of sadness.
戸惑うことないなんて嘘はつかないよ
I won't lie and say I'm never bewildered.
空に舞うコインが描く
The parabola drawn by the coin
放物線が決める運命
dancing in the sky decides fate.
打ち出した答えが今日も
The answer I've struck out courses
私の胸を駆け巡る
through my chest again today.
Sparkling shiny lights awake true desire
Only my railgun can shoot it 必ず
Only my railgun can shoot it, definitely.
貫いてく 戸惑うことなく
I'll pierce through without hesitation.
傷ついても 走り続ける
Even if I'm hurt, I'll keep running.
狙え！ 凛と煌く視線は
Aim! My dignified and sparkling gaze
狂いなく闇を切り裂く
cuts through the darkness without fail.
迷いなんて 吹き飛ばせばいい
Just blow away your doubts.
この心が叫ぶ限り
As long as this heart screams,
誰ひとり邪魔などさせない
I won't let anyone get in the way.
はかなく舞う無数の願いは
Countless fleeting wishes
この両手に積もってゆく
pile up in these hands.
切り裂く闇に見えてくるのは
What I see in the darkness I cut through
重く深く切ない記憶
are heavy, deep, and painful memories.
色褪せてく現実に揺れる
Swaying in the fading reality,
絶望には負けたくない
I don't want to lose to despair.
私が今私であることを胸を張って
I can proudly boast that I am who I am
全て誇れる
right now, and be proud of it all.
Looking the blitz loop this planet to search a way
Only my railgun can shoot it 今すぐ
Only my railgun can shoot it, right now.
身体中を光の速さで
At the speed of light through my whole body,
駆け巡った 確かな予感
a certain premonition coursed through.
放て！ 心に刻んだ夢を
Release it! The dream etched in your heart
未来さえも置き去りにした
left even the future behind.
限界など知らない 意味ない
I know no limits, they're meaningless.
この力が光散らす
This power scatters light.
その先に遥かな想いを
Beyond that, far-reaching thoughts.
#沙花叉アニソンフェス
#SakamataAnisongFes
はい！ということで、すみません、よだれで溺れましたが、ちょっと許してください。
Yes! So, sorry, I choked on my own spit, but please forgive me.
えー、沙花叉アニソンフェスということで、ちょっとみんなが知っていたりとかね、
Um, since this is the Sakamata Anisong Fes, I've performed some songs that everyone knows,
個人的に沙花叉が好きな曲を披露させていただきました。
or that I personally like.
どうだったでしょうか？みんな、いい感じだった？
How was it? Was it good, everyone?
ちょっとここ見てますよ。いい感じでしたか？
I'm looking at the chat here. Was it good?
トレンド1位も、ありがとうございます！本当にありがとう。
Thank you for the #1 trend too! Truly, thank you.
あの、よかったら、こっちかな？こっちだ。
Um, if you'd like, is it this way? This way.
えー、沙花叉アニソンフェスで、呟いてください。よろしくお願いします。
Please tweet with the hashtag #SakamataAnisongFes. Thank you.
ホント選曲神だった？ありがとうございます！
Was the setlist really god-tier? Thank you!
あ、ということでですね、ちょっと改めてなんですけれども、えー、たくさんのね、ホロックス5人揃っての...
Ah, and so, just once again, um, many... all five of HoloX together...
今まではね、あの…5人、坂本さんと合わせて5人ですよね？
Until now, there were... five, right? Five including Sakamoto-san.
5人揃ってのゲストが今までは普通だったんですけど。
Having five guests together was the norm until now.
今回、なんと先輩方を誘ったり、あとMay'nさんがね、来ていただいたりなど。
This time, I invited my seniors, and even May'n-san came to perform.
結構スペシャルな1日になったんじゃないかなと思うんですが。
I think it's become quite a special day.
どうだったでしょうか？
What did you think of it?
びっくりしたでしょ？絶対ゲスト予想当てられないと思ったんだよね。
You were surprised, weren't you? I knew you'd never guess the guests.
もうね、5番の予想は絶対に外れると思って出しました。
I put out that fifth guess thinking everyone would definitely get it wrong.
意地悪しました、すみません。すみません。
I was being mean, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
ということでですね、えー、まあまたステージの方もね。
And so, well, the stage too...
色々作ってもらってめちゃめちゃ良かったんですが。
They made so many things for it, and it turned out great.
こちらの振り返りの方でお話しさせていただければと思います。
I'd like to talk about it more during the look-back section.
しっかり紹介したいので。めちゃいいっすね、これでもね。
Because I want to introduce it properly. It's really cool, isn't it?
めちゃめちゃいい。フェス会場。ありがとうございます。
The festival venue is amazing. Thank you so much.
ではですね、配信も丁度半分終わったところなので。
Now then, since we're exactly halfway through the stream...
今日は企画を持ってきました。
I've brought a special segment for today.
じゃじゃーん。せっかくのアニソンフェスということで。
Ta-da! Since this is an Anisong Festival...
せーの！「サカマタ生アフレコ」！
Ready, go! "Sakamata Live Dubbing"!
イエーイ！
Yay!
サカマタ生アフレコ
Sakamata Live Dubbing
はい、こちらですね。ちょっとどういったものなのかっていうのを説明させてください。
Yes, this is it. Let me explain what it is.
今からですね、過去にもう公開済みのホロぐらのVTRを流しながら。
I'll play a HoloGra clip that's already been released...
沙花叉が生アフレコをしていきたいと思います。
And I, Sakamata, will dub it live.
まず最初はこちらです。
First up is this one.
はい、「世界征服は沙花叉した」です。覚えてますか？
Yes, "World Domination Has Begun". Do you remember it?
それではまずは実際に投稿された映像の一部を見ていきましょう。どうぞ！
First, let's watch a part of the original footage. Here you go!
2022/11/27 世界征服は沙花叉した
2022/11/27 World Domination Has Begun
まずは世界征服の議題。
First, the agenda for world domination.
足がかりにホロライブを…
As a foothold, Hololive will...
何でこんな高いんだよ！おい、インターン！
Why is it so high! Hey, intern!
寝てるね。
She's sleeping.
起きろ！
Wake up!
価値観を根こそぎ変えろ。
Change their values entirely.
それ何の意味があるの？
What's the point of that?
学ぶは真似ぶと言うか。
Well, they say learning is imitating.
つまり。
In other words.
何も分かってないでしょ。おい、真面目に会議して！
You don't get it at all. Hey, take this meeting seriously!
はい、これがね、その回の代一部なんですけれども。
Yes, that was a part of that episode.
ちょっとこの回のアフレコをしていきたいと思うんですが。
I'm going to try dubbing this episode live.
別にタイミングとか出されるわけじゃないので、マジで、あの空気読みです。
Since there are no timing cues, I'll have to read the room.
覚えてるかどうかの記憶力ゲーです。
It's a game of memory to see if I remember it all.
では行きたいと思います。お願いします。
All right, let's do this. Here we go.
ござる！
Gozaru!
ずら！
Zura!
掃除中！
Cleaning in progress!
イエス、マイ・ダーク！
Yes, My Dark!
行くぞ、野郎共！
Let's go, guys!
今日は気分じゃないかもしれない…
Maybe I'm not in the mood today...
えー！？
Eh!?
作戦会議日和かもしれない。
Maybe it's a good day for a strategy meeting.
ぶえー！
Buehh!
ござる！
Gozaru!
掃除中！
Cleaning in progress!
ずら！
Zura!
マイ・ダーク！
My Dark!
ホロックス！イエーイ！
HoloX! Yay!
寝てるね。
She's sleeping.
起きろ！
Wake up!
起きた。痛い。
I'm awake. Ouch.
何の意味があるの？
What's the point?
真似ぶ。
Imitate.
つまり。
In other words.
意味分かってない。何で痛い。ちゃんと。
You don't understand. Why does it hurt? Be serious.
ルイの頭脳が必要だ。
We need Lui's intellect.
お願いします。
Please do.
刮目せよ！
Witness this!
それ、吾輩のセリフ！
That's my line!
何ができるの？シャボン玉が出る。
What can you do? Bubbles will come out.
何の意味があるの？
What's the point of that?
世界中の子供達がこれに夢中になり。
Children all over the world will be obsessed with this.
どこもかしこもシャボン液まみれに。
Everywhere will be covered in bubble solution.
世界がどんどんベトベトになっていき。
The world will become stickier and stickier.
お風呂の回数が極端に増え。
The number of baths will increase dramatically.
みんなリラックスして、油断したところ。
When everyone is relaxed and off guard...
ホロックスが叩く！
HoloX strikes!
そうはならんやろ！
That's not how it works!
ほいっ、はっ、遊ぶな！
Hup, ha! Stop playing around!
いろはちゃん。クロた。
Iroha-chan. Chloe.
何？
What?
総帥、こちらへ。
Leader, this way.
敵兵は一つ、単身で乗り込んでくるとはね。
One enemy troop, coming in alone.
てけてけてけてけ。
Pitter-patter pitter-patter.
目標は？分かんないから。
Objective? I don't know.
誰か助けて！
Someone, help!
大丈夫ですよ。
It's all right.
沙花叉、風真、接敵！
Sakamata, Kazama, engage the enemy!
ほえっ、ほえー。
Hoe? Hoee.
いえーい。
Yay.
にゃーん。
Meow.
ほげーっ！猫！
Hogee! A cat!
あい！
Eye!
いや、本当に相変わらずホロぐらでしたね。
Wow, that really was classic HoloGra.
はい、でも今回ちょっとやった一本目はですね。
Yes, but this first one I did...
セリフ少ない方なんですよ。
It was one of the ones with fewer lines.
1本目は猫ずこうもなんとなく覚えてたんですけど、
I vaguely remembered 'Neko Zukou' for the first one,
2本目めちゃくちゃセリフ多いです。
but the second one has a ton of lines.
2本目こちら！
Here's the second one!
サカマタ生アフレコ
Sakamata Live Dubbing
2022/11/20 実体の無い雑魚に負けるわけない！……よね？
Nov 20, 2022 - There's no way I'd lose to a non-existent small fry! ...Right?
では、また実際の映像の一部を見てください。
Now, please take a look at a portion of the actual footage.
どうぞ！
Here you go!
真っ暗。説明しよう。
It's pitch black. Let me explain.
なんか起きたら夜になってて、誰もいないし帰りたいんだけど、
I woke up and it was night, nobody's around and I want to go home,
あ、鍵持ってないじゃん。
but oh, I don't have my keys.
流石に戸締りしないのはまずいかなーって。
I thought it'd be bad not to lock up.
だから帰るに帰れないわけよ。
So I just can't go home.
とりあえず。
Anyway.
いや、マジでね、全然覚えてないっすけど。
No, seriously, I don't remember it at all.
ちょっとやっていきたいと思います。
But I'm going to give it a try.
クソほどセリフあるんで、あの、なんか声が遅れて聞こえてきたらね、
There are so many lines, so if my voice sounds lagged,
それはみんなのせいです！
that's on you guys!
じゃ、いきます！
Okay, here I go!
真っ暗。説明しよう。
It's pitch black. Let me explain.
なんか起きたら夜になってて、誰もいないし帰りたいんだけど、
I woke up and it was night, nobody's around and I want to go home,
あ、鍵持ってないじゃん。
but oh, I don't have my keys.
流石に戸締りしないのはまずいかなーって。
I thought it'd be bad not to lock up.
だから帰るに帰れないわけよ。
So I just can't go home.
とりあえず。
Anyway.
あれ？
Huh?
ん？あれ？セリフのある、あれ？
Mm? Huh? Where there are lines, wait...
どこで喋ってるんですか？あなた。
Where are you talking from?
えっ、した？
Eh? Below?
まーじ、タピオカも最近きつそうだもんね。
Seriously, even Tapioca seems to be having a hard time lately.
ラップ現象だ。
It's a poltergeist.
つまりこの部屋にいるのは...
In other words, the one in this room is...
会いに来るな！
Don't come to see me!
だ、しかし、し、し、し、し！
B-but, h-h-h-h!
実体のない雑魚に負けるサカマタで...
A Sakamata who loses to a non-existent small fry—
ぎゃあああ！
AAAAAAAH!
わしじゃよ。小気味よいシャドウ音が聞こえたのでな。
It's me. I heard some pleasant shadow sounds.
サカマタ！
Sakamata!
ううう...
Uuu...
いや、完璧でしたね。
Man, that was perfect.
よかった。
Glad it went well.
もう一寸の狂いもなく、はい、いけましたね。
Not a single error, yup, I nailed it.
大丈夫でしたね。
It was fine, right?
はい、ということで、サカマタ生アフレコでしたー！
Alright, and that was the Sakamata Live Dubbing segment!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ではですね、この後ライブがラストスパートに向けて、
Now, after this, the live performance is going to speed up
ちょっと加速していくんですけど、
for the final stretch,
まだまだ盛り上がっていきますかー！
but are you guys ready to get even more hyped?!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ではですね、この後なんとゲストの方々にも
Now, we actually have some guests
生配信で出演していただきます。
who will be appearing on the livestream.
ちょっとね、ゲストの皆さんも含めて一緒に応援しててください。
Please cheer them on along with me.
それでは、ラストスパート最初のゲストはこの方です！
And now, the first guest of the final stretch is... this person!
コホン、皆さーん！
Ahem, hello everyone!
どうもこんばんはー！
Good evening!
森カリオペです。What's up Chloe-chan?
It's Mori Calliope. What's up, Chloe-chan?
カリ先輩！
Calli-senpai!
いやもう、めっちゃ緊張してましたけど、
Man, I was so nervous,
カリ先輩が堂々とこう来てくれて、安心しました、今。
but seeing Calli-senpai come out so confidently really put me at ease.
余裕余裕ですよ。
Piece of cake, piece of cake.
ちょっと楽しみましょうよ！
Let's have some fun!
Let's go, 派手にぶちかまそうぜ！
Let's go, let's go out with a bang!
イエーイ！ Let's rock!
Yay! Let's rock!
Hey everybody! Are you ready? Let's go!
Counteraction rising
Yeah we are ready for the punch line
There's no use with all your gimmicks
So check this out!
Login you damned one's
Crush the won't you come
The noise comes we are ready to bow
What about the antidote for the jammed and hypnotized
Rend the lie that covers
咲き乱れた花のように 鮮やかな痛み抱き
Like flowers blooming in profusion, embracing a vivid pain
佇む街を抜け 迷いのセリフは捨て
Passing through the standing city, throwing away the lines of hesitation
帰らない声よ響け We say wow
Echo, oh voice that won't return! We say wow
Database, database, just living in the database, wow wow
The wall of pure fictions cracking in my head
And the addiction of my world still spreads
In the database, database, I'm struggling in the database, wow wow
It doesn't even matter if there is no hope at all
As the madness of the system grows
Crack in the key for the real clue
Mask presentation reigning on but we know we've been longing for this
Cut it out
The plot that deceived you
Drop the rebel sound
Shut the system down
Reveal the never-found
いつか見た夢を
A dream I once saw
残酷な現実とも見える瓦礫の中で
In the midst of debris that looks like cruel reality
戦い続けるだけ
I just keep on fighting
Get them all from bigger heads, yeah!
You get them all from bigger heads!
重なる世界で滾る心に火を灯して
Light a fire in the boiling heart in overlapping worlds
Database, database, just living in the database, wow wow
The wall of pure fiction's cracking in my head
And the addiction of my world's dispersed in the database
Database, database, I'm struggling in the database, wow wow
It doesn't even matter if there is no hope
Just say wow wow
Hey wait a minute, what happened? The data's wrong! Come on!
Shake it! Rock it!
盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get pumped up!
時に計算高さは蛇足で Calculator
Sometimes calculation is redundant, Calculator
統計に揺さぶられたまま消えてった
It disappeared while being shaken by statistics
そうなりたくなきゃ Database
If you don't want that, Database
だけに頼らず磨け自分のペース yeah
Don't just rely on that, polish your own pace, yeah
Database, database, just living in the database, wow wow
The wall of pure fiction's cracking in my head
And the addiction of my world's dispersed in the database
Database, database, I'm struggling in the database, wow wow
It doesn't even matter if there is no hope
As the madness of the system grows
Database, database, just living in the database
Database, database, just say wow wow
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
楽しかった！
That was fun!
楽しかったです、最高！
It was fun, the best!
本当に最高の感じ！
Truly the best feeling!
いいライブです！
It's a great live!
おめでとうございます、クロヱちゃん！
Congratulations, Chloe-chan!
ありがとうございます！本当に嬉しい！
Thank you very much! I'm really happy!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
私も楽しかった！
I had fun too!
これからも頑張ってくださいね！
Please keep doing your best!
頑張ります！イェーイ！
I will! Yeah!
Okay, bye bye!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
Peace!
はい、ということで...
Yes, and so...
カリ先輩を交えての「database」でした！
That was "database" with Calli-senpai!
ではでは、最後のゲスト...
Now then, the final guest...
呼んじゃおうかな？どうしようかな？
Shall I call them out? What should I do?
呼ばないっていう手もありますかね？
Is there an option not to call them?
呼んでよ！
Call me!
来ちゃった！来ちゃった！
She came! She came!
呼んでよ！
Call me!
来ちゃった！どなたですか？
She came! Who is it?
彗星のごとくあらわれたスターの原石！アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！よろしくお願いいたします！
The diamond in the rough that appeared like a comet! I'm Idol VTuber Hoshimachi Suisei! Nice to meet you!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Nice to meet you!
ちょっと疲れてるんじゃないですか？
Aren't you a bit tired?
いやいや、まだまだっすよ！
No no, I'm still going!
いけるんですか？
Can you do it?
いきますよ！
I'll do it!
じゃあ、いってやりましょうよ！
Then let's go for it!
ぶちこます、あの曲を！
Let's unleash that song!
いきまそう！
Let's go!
Please don't say you are lazy, だって本当は crazy
Please don't say you are lazy, because actually you're crazy
白鳥たちはそう、見えないとこでバタ足するんです
Swans are like that, they paddle under the water where you can't see
本能に忠順忠実、本能も重々承知
Obedient and faithful to instinct, well aware of the instinct
前途洋々だし、だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
The future is bright, so I take a break once in a while
はいはいはい！すいぐいいけるのか？！
Yeah yeah yeah! Can you go further?!
この眼でしっかり定めて行き先、秩序はアクシデント
Looking firmly with these eyes at the destination, order is an accident
近道あればそれが思うツボ、拗ねる翼もあれば上等
If there's a shortcut, it's just as intended, if there are stubborn wings, even better
ヤバ、爪は割れた、グルーで補修した
Oh no, my nail broke, I fixed it with glue
それだけでなんか達成感
Just that gives a sense of accomplishment
大事なのは自分、可愛がること
The important thing is to cherish yourself
自分を愛さなきゃ、他人も愛せない
If you don't love yourself, you can't love others
Please don't say you are lazy, だって本当は crazy
Please don't say you are lazy, because actually you're crazy
能ある鷹はそう、見えないとこでピークを出すんです
We are like that, we peak where you can't see
想像に一生懸命、現実は絶対絶命
Dedicated to imagination, reality is a desperate situation
発展途中だし、だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
In the middle of development, so I take a break once in a while
お気に入りの服に ビーチ外れるんだ
With my favorite clothes, the beach slips away...
あぁ そんなに見つめないで
Ah, don't stare at me like that.
いつでも全力で夢見て その分全力で眠って
Always dreaming with all my might, sleeping just as hard.
ほら、ね、ちょい痩せたい
See, hey, I want to lose a little weight.
調子ついて食った
I got carried away and ate.
それだけ? なんで? 全保管!
Is that all? Why? Store it all!
透かさずに目標を下方修正して
Without missing a beat, lower the goals.
柔軟に臨機応変、百変化勝ち!
Adaptable and flexible, a hundred changes to win!
Please don't say you are lazy
だって本当はcrazy
Because actually, I'm crazy.
孔雀たちはそう
Peacocks are like that,
ここぞという時 美を見せるんです
They show their beauty when the time is right.
想像増しまし ガチ恋送信レイジー
Imagination maxed out, sending serious love lazy.
弱気はずだし だからやけに意志だけ強いんです
I'm weak-willed, so only my determination is unusually strong.
坂又さーん！
Sakamata-san!
はい、ここで、はい、決着をつけましょう！
Yes, let's settle this right here!
いきますか！
Shall we go?!
最初はグー、ジャンケン、ホイ！
Rock-paper-scissors, shoot!
あっち向いてホイ！
Look that way, hey!
弱っｗｗｗ 最初はグー、ジャンケン、ホイ！
So weak! lol Rock-paper-scissors, shoot!
あいこでしょ！あっち向いてホイ！
It's a tie! Look that way, hey!
よっしゃー！
Alright!
ラストいきますよ！はい！最初はグー、ジャンケン、ホイ！
One last time! Okay! Rock-paper-scissors, shoot!
あいこでしょ！あっち向いてホイ！
It's a tie! Look that way, hey!
最初はグー、ジャンケン、ホイ！あいこでしょ！あっち向いてホイ！
Rock-paper-scissors, shoot! Tie! Look that way, hey!
うぉー！一勝一敗、引き分けー！
Whoa! One win, one loss, it's a draw!
やばっ！まさか連敗? いい加減クリア
Oh no! A losing streak? Time to clear it already.
それだけ? なんて? 全部カン
Is that all? Like what? All intuition.
大事なのは自分を認めてくこと
The important thing is to acknowledge yourself.
自分を許さなきゃ人も許せない
If you don't forgive yourself, you can't forgive others.
Please don't say you are lazy
だって本当はcrazy
Because actually, I'm crazy.
白鳥たちはそう
Swans are like that,
見えないところでバタ足するんです
They flutter their legs where you can't see.
本能に忠実 翻弄も承知
Faithful to instinct, knowing I'm at its mercy.
前途洋々だし だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
The future is bright, so I take a break once in a while.
決まったぜー！
That's it!
いや何でこれなん、あははは。何でなんですか
Wait, why this? Hahaha. Why is it like this?
ありがとうございましたー！ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much! Thank you!
そしておめでとうー！
And congratulations!
ありがとうございます！めっちゃ楽しかったよー
Thank you! That was so much fun!
一勝一敗ね
One win, one loss, right?
そうですね、次こそ！ね、次こそまた決着を！よろしくお願いいたします！
Right, next time for sure! Let's settle it then! I look forward to it!
では！ありがとうございましたー！またねー！バイバイー！
Well then! Thank you very much! See you! Bye-bye!
はい、というわけでですね、データベースとDon't say 'lazy' 続けてお送りしました。
Alright, and so, we brought you 'Database' and 'Don't say "lazy"' back-to-back.
ありがとうございましたー！イェーイ！
Thank you so much! Yay!
はい、ではいよいよ本当に配信もガチラストスパートとなりました。
Alright, it's finally time for the real final spurt of the stream.
ここで重大なお知らせが2点あります。まず、
I have two major announcements here. First,
皆さんご存知、ま、ご存知ですよね? 坂又クロヱ活動2周年記念グッズー！
As you all know... well, you do know, right? Sakamata Chloe 2nd Anniversary Goods!
沙花叉クロヱ 活動2周年記念
Sakamata Chloe 2nd Anniversary
イェー！…えっ、ちょ、なんかおっぱい毎回増えてません?
Yay! ...Wait, aren't my breasts getting bigger every time?
え、さすがパセリと言ったところでね、本当に可愛らしいキービジュとなっております。
As expected of Parsley-sensei, it's a really lovely key visual.
今回はですね、配信に合わせてフェスの音供になるようなグッズを用意させていただきました。
This time, I've prepared goods that can be your festival companions.
では、紹介したいと思います。まずは、こちら！
Now, let me introduce them. First, this one!
アクリルスタンド
Acrylic Stand
はい、アクリルスタンドですね！やっぱりアクリルスタンド、坂又が好きっていうのもそうなんですが、
Yes, an acrylic stand! Of course, it's because I love them,
お部屋に飾ってほしいなーと思っております。台座もね、結構こだわっていますので、
but I'd love for you to display it in your room. I put a lot of work into the base too,
ま、並べてもいいし、これから出すね、グッズと合わせてもいいなーと思ってます。さあ、次は、こちら！
so you can line them up or pair them with the other goods I'm about to show. Next up is this!
クロヱとおそろいフード付きタオル
Chloe matching hooded towel
はい、クロヱとおそろいフード付きタオルー！やっぱりフェスはタオルっしょ。
Yes, a hooded towel matching Chloe's! You can't have a festival without a towel, right?
ね、タオルないとはじまんないよね、肩にかけたいよね。ということで、フードは取り外し可能となっておりますので、
It doesn't start without one! You want to drape it over your shoulders. The hood is detachable,
是非とも使っていただけると嬉しいな。夏フェスとかにもいいしね、なんかライブとか行くのにもいいかなーと思っております。
so I'd be happy if you'd use it. It's great for summer festivals or when you go to live shows.
坂又とね、おそろっちになってしまうという悪夢ですね。さあ、続いてこちら！
It's a nightmare of being twinsies with me. Anyway, next is this!
サコッシュ
Sacoche
サコッシュです！こちらとね、組み合わせんのもいいかなと思って。
It's a sacoche! I thought it would be nice to pair it with this.
アクスタ非常に可愛らしいデザインになってますよね。これ、ちょっと天才だと思ったんですよね…
The acrylic stand has a very cute design. I really thought this was a stroke of genius...
坂又、デザインの方々、本当ありがとうございます。
Sakamata is so thankful to the designers.
マジで、あの裏地まで可愛いので是非見てみてください。
Seriously, even the lining is cute, so please check it out.
あの、表側はですね、透明になっていますんで、
The front side is transparent,
アクスタとか缶バッジとか、ま、そういうものも入れられますので、
so you can put in things like acrylic stands and badges.
是非オタクグッズとしても活用してみてください。
Please use it to show off your otaku goods.
そして、こちら。
And next is this.
あー、ついに来ちゃったんですね。
Ah, it's finally here.
イヌが、ぬいぐるみマスコットとなりました。
Inu has been made into a plushie mascot.
ついにイヌもですか。
Inu too, finally?
なんか、イヌがなるのムカつくなーと思うんですけど、
It's kind of annoying that Inu got one too, but...
やっぱり可愛らしいので、ちょっと坂又のサコッシュと組み合わせてもいいかなとか思うし、
it's cute, so I think it'd be nice to pair it with Sakamata's sacoche.
なんか、普通にね、坂又のぬいとかフレンズぬいとかありますよね。
There are also the Sakamata and Friends plushies.
そういうのと組み合わせても、まあ可愛いのかなとは思います。
I think it'd be cute to combine it with those as well.
はい、愛でたくなるような可愛さです。
Yes, it's a cuteness you'll want to cherish.
そして最後はこちら。
And finally, this.
はい、シチュエーションボイス「君とのサイン」。
The situation voice, "A Sign with You."
内容はですね、ちょっとこのライブを見た方に、
As for the content, I really wanted to tell those
やっぱりね、ちょっと伝えたいなというのがあって、
who watched this live performance...
少し隠し要素みたいなものがあるの、でよかったら聞いてみてください。
It has some hidden elements, so please give it a listen.
そして、こちらを全部ね、含めたフルセットをご購入いただいた方にはこちらです。
And for those who purchase the full set, you get this.
はい、直筆サイン入りスタッフ風カード。
A staff-pass style card with a handwritten signature.
こちら…、あ、こちらね、スタッフパスとなっております。
This... yes, this is the staff pass.
ねえ、可愛いですよね。ちょっとフェスのスタッフパスっぽくて、めちゃめちゃいいんですよ。
Isn't it cute? It looks like a real festival staff pass.
なんか、後方腕組みオタクできる感じでしょう？
You can act like an otaku standing in the back with your arms crossed.
「あ、なんか、自分スタッフなんで、通りますね」みたいな感じでやってください。
Like, "Oh, I'm staff, so coming through." Give that a try.
あの、本当のフェスでは絶対にやらないでくださいね。よろしくお願いします。
But please, don't ever do that at a real festival. Thank you!
めちゃめちゃいいです。直筆サインもね、今回数量限定なしなので、
It's great. There's no limit on the handwritten signatures this time.
ってか、一回もしたことないんですけど。
Wait, I've never actually done that before.
はい、なしなので、安心してご購入ください。
But yes, since there's no limit, please buy with peace of mind.
あと、もう一個あるか。
Is there one more thing?
なんだっけ。もう一個ありますよね。
What was it? There was something else.
何でしたっけ。え。すいません。
What was it again? Oh, excuse me.
ちょっと、お邪魔します。えーと…、
Let me see... um...
特典ボイスですね。
It's the bonus voice.
特典ボイスはですね、「沙花叉からの秘密のメッセージ」ということでですね。
The bonus voice is a "Secret Message from Sakamata."
こちらはちょっと答え合わせ風というか。
This is kind of like a reveal or explanation.
まあ、ちょっと通常ボイスに近いものでもあるんですけど、
It's similar to a regular voice track,
より特別感溢れたボイスとなっておりますので、是非聞いてください。
but with an extra special feel, so please listen to it.
はい、というわけで、グッズのお知らせでした。
Alright, that was the merchandise announcement.
もう一つのお知らせがあるんですけど、
I have one more announcement,
そちらはみんなの近くで伝えたいなと思うので、ちょっと寄ります。
but I want to tell you up close, so I'll move a bit closer.
はい、というわけで、もう一つのお知らせはですね、
Okay, the next announcement is...
なんと、沙花叉クロヱ、オリジナル曲、リリース決定です！
Sakamata Chloe's original song release is officially decided!
今回の曲はですね、作詞が沙花叉、
For this song, the lyrics were written by Sakamata,
Neko Hackerさんに作曲をしていただいております。
and the music was composed by Neko Hacker.
非常にね、可愛らしくてノリもいい曲なので、是非覚えてほしいなっていうのと、
It's a really cute and catchy song, so I hope you'll learn it.
あのTikTokバズを狙ってます。よろしくお願いします。
I'm aiming for it to go viral on TikTok. Please help me out!
はい、TikTok。あの、皆さんよろしくお願いします。
Yes, TikTok. Everyone, please support it.
はい、22時10分からね、MVプレミアム公開もされますので、よろしくお願いします。
The MV premiere will be at 22:10, so please check it out.
というわけで、こちらのステージで、初披露させていただきたいと思います。
And now, I'd like to perform it for the first time on this stage.
じゃあ、いいですか？準備できてますか？みんな。いきますよ。
Are you ready? Is everyone ready? Here we go.
最後オリ曲。
The last song, my original track.
右左君君右下上目キュルめちょかわです！
Right Left You You Lower-Right Upward-Glance Kyun Super Cute!
あれやこれや言ったって 結局要は顔じゃん？
No matter what you say, in the end, it's all about looks, right?
ずっと側に居るなんて 正直無理が前提じゃん？ ああ
Staying by my side forever... Honestly, isn't that impossible? Ahh
あの子よりも上だって 大体背伸びどんぐりじゃん？
Even if I'm better than her, it's just trying too hard, right?
マジな話神だって リュックの中身パンパンじゃん？
Seriously, even if I'm a god, my backpack is stuffed full, right?
でもでもでも君となら
But, but, but if it's with you...
目指す真っ直ぐでひた向きで 心掴む理想の子に
I'll aim straight and wholeheartedly to be your ideal girl.
見て？頭の先から爪まで
Look? From the top of my head to my toenails,
君好みカスタムスタイル
I'm in a custom style that you like.
調子に乗って落ち込んで 泣いちゃう日もあるけど
Getting carried away and then feeling down, I cry sometimes, but...
さあロケラングレラン君タゲ
Now, rocket launcher, grenade launcher, targeting you.
もう爆弾あるだけぶち込め (どかーん！)
Throw in every bomb I have! (Kaboom!)
爆風もくふわ♡決めたら
Once the blast clears into a fluffy puff...
文句はこれでないね？
You won't have any complaints now, right?
右左君君右上向きゃるんめちゃかわ！
Right, left, you, you, looking up-right, so cute!
（ふわふわ！）
(Fluffy!)
斜め右あざとさ舌ペロマジ顔もめちゃかわいい！
Sly glance right, tongue out, your serious face is so cute!
夜ふかし極めて逆に健康だ
Staying up late to the extreme makes me healthy instead
「宿題10週過ぎてます！」
"Homework is 10 weeks overdue!"
「炎上だけは勘弁です」
"Please, anything but a controversy."
(そうは言われても約束できない
(Even if you say that, I can't promise
好きな事だけ爆速でいたい)
I want to go full speed with only things I like)
「そんな所も大好きです！」
"I love that about you too!"
「今日も生きててえらちゃんです！」
"Good job for living today too!"
(そう褒められると申し訳ない…
(When praised like that, I feel bad...
期待下潜った人間です…)
I'm just a person who fell below expectations...)
でもでも君だから
But, but, because it's you
誓うまっすぐにひた向きに
I swear, straightforwardly and single-mindedly
心揺らす君の為に
For you, who shakes my heart
ほら頭の先から爪まで
Look, from the tip of my head to my nails
君好みのナチュラルスタイル
A natural style just for you
うさちゃんパジャマのままだし
Still in my bunny pajamas
5度寝する日もあるけど
Even if I sleep in five times some days
でもいつでもエイムは君タゲ
But my aim is always targeting you
もう残弾ないけど撃ち抜け（ずきゅーん！）
No more ammo left, but shoot through (Bang!)
調子に乗っても良いよね？
It's okay to get carried away, right?
文句は後で聞きます…
I'll listen to your complaints later...
右左君君右上向きゃるんめちゃかわ！
Right, left, you, you, looking up-right, so cute!
（ふわふわ！）
(Fluffy!)
斜め右あざとさ舌ペロマジ顔もめちゃかわいい！
Sly glance right, tongue out, your serious face is so cute!
2周年ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for the 2nd anniversary!
3周年目も、みんなよろしくねー！
Please take care of me in our 3rd year too, everyone!
楽しかった！ありがとう！
That was fun! Thank you!